<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Rich Paulo</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Rich Paulo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate SMS and MMS with R, Twilio, Docker, and Github Actions</title>
      <link>/blog/docker-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/docker-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>Salvador Dali, &amp;ldquo;The Disintegration of The Persistence of Memory&amp;rdquo; 1952.
Introduction   My mother grew up as the youngest of 6 children in Thailand, after her family emigrated from China during the Chinese Civil Wars. While growing up in Bangkok&amp;rsquo;s Chinatown, my mother learned English from Christian missionaries, and eventually immigrated to the United States.
First a devout Buddhist, and later a devout Christian, my mom&amp;rsquo;s core values have always included love and compassion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parquet, SQL, DuckDB, arrow, dbplyr and R</title>
      <link>/blog/parquet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/parquet/</guid>
      <description>French tapestry, &amp;ldquo;Jesuits performing astronomy with Chinese&amp;rdquo;
Introduction     As opposed to traditional row-based storage (e.g., SQL), Parquet files (.parquet) are columnar-based, and feature efficient compression (fast read/write and small disk usage) and optimized performance for big data. Writing to parquet data format and partitioning (splitting the data across multiple files for faster querying) is relatively trivial in R with the {arrow} package which provides arrow::write_dataset(). There are a few options for querying Parquet data from R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install RStudio Server on Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>/blog/azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/azure/</guid>
      <description>How to install R and RStudio Server on an Azure Virtual Machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aquifer thickness calculated from ~300,000 well logs</title>
      <link>/blog/aquifer-thickness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 02:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/aquifer-thickness/</guid>
      <description>Data visualization from hundreds of thousands of well completion reports reveals aquifer characteristics in California groundwater basins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
